One Bowl of Tea on Rice
One bowl of tea on rice.
一杯の茶漬け
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
Pickled plums, slivered nori,
梅干に刻み海苔
それに夕餉の残りの鶏肉
and leftover chicken from dinner.
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
All doused in piping-hot water,
そいつを熱い白湯に浮かべ
诸神微信公众号正式上线啦，搜索「诸神字幕组」添加关注吧
塩昆布と一緒に掻き込む
then shoveled in with salted kelp.
That was so good.
旨かったなあ
All those bowls of tea on rice I'd sneak into the kitchen to make at the orphanage...
孤児院の台所で人目を忍んで食った茶漬けは
Ow!
Damn it...
駄目だ　腹減って死ぬ
I'm gonna die of hunger.
僕の名前は敦
My name is Atsushi.
Episode 1
Fortune is Unpredictable
and Mutable
Due to certain circumstances,
I'm about to die from starvation.
故あって　餓死寸前です
After being driven out of the orphanage,
孤児院を追い出され　食べるものも寝るところもなく
I had nothing to eat, nowhere to sleep,
and, as one might expect, not a cent to my name.
勿論金もなく
かといって盗みを働く度胸もなく
Yet, I lack the courage to commit theft.
That is how I've arrived at my current predicament.
こんな処まで来てしまった
しかし…
However...
If I wish to live,
最早生きたければ　盗むか奪うしかない
I have no choice but to steal and take from others!
Get out, you failure!
出ていけ　穀潰し
No orphanage would ever welcome the likes of you!
お前などこの孤児院にも要らぬ
どこぞで野垂れ死にでもしたほうが世間様の為よ
The world would be a better place
if you'd just die in a ditch somewhere!
五月蝿い
Shut up...
Shut up!
五月蝿い
五月蝿ァーい
Die in a ditch?
野垂れ死にだと
I'm not gonna die!
僕は死なないぞ　絶対に
I'm gonna live, no matter what it takes!
何としても生き延びてやる
Alright.
よし　この次に通りかかった奴を襲って　そいつから金品を奪ってやる
I'll attack the first person who comes along
and rob them of everything they have!
Well, that was mission impossible.
流石にこれは無理だ　空腹じゃ追いつけない
I can't catch him on an empty stomach.
Next!
次っ
１２３４　１２３４　１２３４　１２３４…
One, two, three, four!
ト　トレーニング中の軍警が財布を持ってるとは思えない
I... I doubt military police would be toting their wallets during training.
But the next person who comes along... for sure!
次だ　次こそ絶対に
今度こそっ
I've got this!
いや…
Well...
これは流石にノーカンでしょ
I can't possibly count him.
ノ　ノーカンにさせてください
Y-Yeah, I'll pass, please.
I... I'll pass...
ノ　ノーカンにィー
Fine!
In the end...
...I saved a life?
You were floating down the river...
川に流されてましたけど　大丈夫ですか
Are you okay?
I made it.
助かったか
ちぇっ
Damn.
「ちぇっ」？
"Damn"?
Did he just say "damn"?
今「ちぇっ」って云ったか　この人
君かい　私の入水を邪魔したのは
Are you the one who interrupted my drowning?
僕はただ助けようとしただけで
I was just trying to help.
Huh?
入水？
Drowning?
Submersion...
知らんかね
You don't know what I mean by that?
入水　自殺だよ
I was trying to commit suicide.
じ　自殺？
...Suicide?
Suicide!?
That's right, I was trying to commit suicide.
そう　私は自殺をしようとしていたのだ
それなのに　君が余計なことを
But you just had to interfere.
Why...
...am I being
lectured?
Wait, is he scolding me for saving him?
僕なんか今怒られてる？
Still, my priority is to commit a clean suicide
とはいえ　人に迷惑をかけないクリーンな自殺が私の信条だ
without troubling others.
Yet, I did trouble you,
だのに　君に迷惑をかけた時点でそれはこちらの落ち度
so the fault lies with me at this point.
何かお詫びでも…
I should apologize in some way.
Growl
Are you hungry, boy?
空腹なのかい　少年
実は　ここ数日何も食べてなくて…
Well..
I haven't eaten in several days.
Growl
Ugh...
How odd.
Growl
奇遇だな
I'm also hungry.
実は私もだ
Then...
それじゃあ…
ちなみに財布は流されたようだ
By the way, the river seems to have taken my wallet.
You can't be serious.
そんな…
こんな処に居ったか　唐変木
There you are, blockhead!
Oh, hey.
Nice work, Kunikida-kun.
国木田君　ご苦労様ァー
何がご苦労様だ　苦労は凡てお前の所為だ　この自殺嗜癖
Nice work?
And just who caused all this work,
you suicidal maniac?!
I've had enough of you disrupting my schedule!
お前はどれだけ俺の計画を乱せば気が済むのだ
あ　そうだ
Oh, right!
よいことを思いついた
I have a great idea.
He's a colleague of mine from work.
彼は私の同僚なのだ　彼に奢ってもらえばいい
Let's have him treat you to a meal.
Are you even listening to me?!
人の話を聞けよ
君　名前は？
What's your name?
Huh?
中島…敦ですけど
Nakajima... Atsushi.
Well, come along, Atsushi-kun!
では　ついて来たまえ　敦君
What would you like to eat?
何が食べたい
あの…　できれば…
Um...
Well, if it's not too much trouble...
なァに　遠慮は要らないよ
Oh, there's no need to hold back!
I'd like to eat tea on rice.
茶漬けが食べたいです
So a boy on the brink of starvation
wants to eat tea on rice?
餓死寸前の少年が茶漬けを所望か
いいよ　国木田君に三十杯くらい奢らせよう
Very well, let's have Kunikida-kun
treat you to thirty bowls!
Don't get all generous with my money, Dazai!
俺の金で太っ腹になるな　太宰
Dazai?
太宰？
ああ　私の名だよ
Yeah, that's my name.
I am Dazai.
私の名は太宰
Dazai Osamu.
太宰治だ
You're unbelievable.
全く　貴様という奴は
仕事中に「いい川だね」とか云いながらいきなり飛び込む奴があるか
Who says “What a nice river!"
and then jumps into it in the middle of a job?!
Thanks to you, look!
おかげで見ろ　予定が大幅に遅れてしまった
See how off-schedule we are now!
国木田君は予定表が好きだねえ
You sure like your schedules, Kunikida-kun.
Ideal
これは予定表ではない
This isn't a schedule!
This is an ideal!
理想だ
My guide in life!
我が人生の道標だ
そしてこれには
And nowhere in this book
is it written that my work partner is a suicidal maniac!
「仕事の相方が自殺嗜癖」とは書いていない
Suicidal maniac?
＄％＃＠＆＃％＊＄＠
Shut up!
五月蝿い
Nowhere on my projected expenses
page will you find written
出費計画の頁にも
「俺の金で小僧がしこたま茶漬けを食う」とは書いていない
that I will buy a million bowls of
tea on rice for a snot-nosed brat!
＃＊％＆＠＊＄？
Snot-nosed brat?
Like I said, it's a job!
だから仕事だ
＆＠％＃＄＃＄＃＄？
What kind of job?
Our job today?
今日の仕事？　軍関係の依頼だが
It involves the military.
How are you two communicating, actually?
なんで君達会話できてるの
I'm so full.
食ったー
もう茶漬けは十年は見たくない
I don't want to see another bowl
of this for at least ten years.
お前…
Why, you!
人の金でこれだけ食っておいて　よくもまあ抜け抜けと
How dare you be so shameless
after eating on my dime?
You're a real lifesaver!
本当助かりました
After leaving the orphanage and
coming to Yokohama,
孤児院を出て横浜に来てから　食べるものも寝るところもなく
I've had nothing to eat and nowhere to sleep.
I thought I'd have an untimely death.
あわや餓死するかと
君　施設の出かい
You're from an institute?
You could say that.
出というか…
But they chased me out.
追い出されたんです
それは薄情な施設もあったものだね
That's some non-profit there.
おい　太宰
Hey, Dazai!
俺達は恵まれぬ小僧に慈悲を垂れる篤志家じゃない
We're not some philanthropists going around helping brats down on their luck, okay?
Let's get back to the job at hand.
仕事に戻るぞ
That reminds me, you said earlier that your current job involves the military.
そういえば先刻　軍関係の依頼と仰ってましたが
What is your line of work, exactly?
何のお仕事を？
なァに　探偵だよ
Oh, we're just detectives.
探偵？
Detectives...?
That's not to say we only
handle lost pets and infidelity.
探偵と云っても　ペット探しや不貞調査ではないぞ
The Armed Detective Agency,
異能集団「武装探偵社」と云えば　聞いたことがあるのではないか
an organization of supernatural detectives
Perhaps you've heard of us.
What?
風の噂で聞いたことがあった「武装探偵社」
I've heard of this Armed Detective Agency in rumors...
曰く　軍や警察に頼れない危険な仕事を専門にする探偵集団
Said to be an agency specializing in missions
that cannot be entrusted to the
likes of the police or the military.
A twilight armed force positioned
between the world of night and day.
昼の世界と夜の世界　その間を取り仕切る薄暮の武装集団
I'm told many from the Agency
possess supernatural powers...
何でも「武装探偵社」の社員の多くが異能力を持つ者だと聞くが
but does that also apply to these two?
この二人がそうなのか
あんな処にいい鴨居がっ
Check out that nice beam up there.
Don't analyze whether you can hang yourself in a random teahouse we just found!
立ち寄った茶屋で首吊りの算段をするな
違うよ　首吊り健康法だよ
Don't get me wrong.
We're talking the hanging health method.
何だ　それは
What's that about?
What, you don't know?!
国木田君知らないの　凄く肩凝りに効くのに
It's so good for shoulder cramps!
なに　そんな健康法ある…
What?!
Such a thing exists?!
ほら　メモメモ　早く
Hey, write this all down!
首吊り健康法…
Hanging... health... method...
嘘だけど
I'm messing with you.
A-Are these two really with the
Armed Detective Agency?
こ　この二人が本当にあの武装探偵社？
相棒は川に流されるわ
My partner gets himself washed up in a river,
行き倒れの小僧は遠慮もなく食いまくるわで
and a brat on death's door just
stuffs himself with no shame.
俺の完璧な予定が今や白紙同然だ
My schedule for the day was just perfect,
今日の仕事だけは予定通り終わらせるからな
but I have to start over from square one!
So, about your job today...
I'll ensure that the job will be
finished on schedule, if nothing else!
その　今日のお仕事というのは
わかったか　この唐変木
ああァ？
Yeah?!
Sorry, I shouldn't have asked!
すいません　余計なこと聞いちゃいました
そ…そそうですよね　探偵社の仕事は守秘義務とかありますもんね
R-Right, of course your jobs are classified!
今日の仕事は別に隠すような類のものではない
Today's job doesn't really require secrecy.
We're looking for a certain tiger
on behest of the military.
軍の依頼で　虎探しをしている
A tiger?
虎？
近頃街を荒らしている噂の「人喰い虎」だよ
A man-eater who's recently appeared in these parts.
Well, not that we know for sure if it's devoured anyone,
ま　ほんとに人を食ったかは知らないが
倉庫を荒らしたり　畑の作物を食ったり　好き放題さ
but it's ransacked warehouses and
eaten farm produce and the like,
doing whatever it wants.
最近　この辺りでの目撃情報が多くてね
It's been spotted around here lately.
What's wrong, Atsushi-kun?
どうした　敦君
I... I... I'll be leaving now.
ぼ…ぼぼ…ぼ僕はこ…これで失礼します　さ…さようなら
G-Good-bye.
Wait, brat!
待て　小僧
You know something, don't you?
貴様　何か知っているな
む…無理だ
You can't.
No one can take it on!
奴に人が敵うわけない
貴様　「人喰い虎」を知っているのか
You know of the man-eating tiger?
It's after me.
あいつは僕を狙ってる　殺されかけたんだ
It almost killed me!
If it's been seen around here,
この辺に出たんなら　早く逃げないと
I have to run, now!
Hey, brat!
小僧
You'll either pay for the food with your arm or by telling us everything.
茶漬け代は腕一本か凡て話すかだな
まあまあ　国木田君
Now, now, Kunikida-kun.
Whenever you try to ask questions,
君がやると情報収集が尋問になる
it becomes an interrogation.
社長にいつも注意されてるだろ
The Boss's been talking to you about this.
And...
それで　君はあの虎の何を知ってる
what do you know about this tiger?
うちの孤児院はあの虎に　ぶっ壊されたんです
My orphanage was decimated by that tiger.
It ravaged our fields,
畑を荒らされ
鳥小屋も壊され
it ravaged our chicken coop,
それに倉庫も
and even our warehouse.
死人こそ出なかったけど
No one died, sure,
but the orphanage was
already on a shoestring budget.
貧乏孤児院がそれで立ち行かなくなって　口減らしに僕は追い出された
I got kicked out so they
had one less mouth to feed.
Get out, you failure!
出ていけ　穀潰し
The world would be a better place if you'd just die in a ditch somewhere!
どこぞで野垂れ死んだほうが世間様の為よ
何故です　僕は何も…
Why me? I didn't do anything...
穀潰しはこの施設には要らん
We don't need worthless louts!
いや　天下のどこにもお前の居場所などありはせん
You'll never find a place where you belong!
Just go! I hope you rot in hell!
どこへでも行き　朽ち果てるがいい
そりゃあ災難だったね
Well, that's tragic.
So, boy, what's this talk about
the tiger almost killing you?
それで小僧　「殺されかけた」というのは
あの「人喰い虎」　僕を追いかけるように
The man-eater always shows up wherever I go.
僕の行くところの先々に現れるんです
Just a while ago, when I was
walking around Tsurumi...
この間も　鶴見の辺りを歩いていた時に
It's a tiger!
虎だ　虎がいるぞ
There's a tiger!
なに
I'd seen it out of the corner of my eyes many times,
施設を追い出された二週間前から　何度もあいつの影を見た
starting two weeks before I
was chased out of the orphanage.
I'm sure it's come all the way
to the city in search of me.
きっと僕を追って　街まで降りてきたんだ
その虎を最後に見たのはいつの話だい
When was the last time you saw the tiger?
I think I saw it around Tsurumi
鶴見の辺りであいつを見たのが　確か四日前です
about four days ago.
It's true that its been focused
around there for the past two weeks.
確かに　虎の被害は二週間前からこっちに集中しているな
それに　四日前に鶴見の辺りで虎の目撃証言もある
In addition, it was sighted around
Tsurumi four days ago.
Atsushi-kun, are you free?
敦君　これから暇？
なんか猛烈に嫌な予感がする
I have a really bad feeling about this.
君が「人喰い虎」に狙われているなら　好都合だ
You being the man-eater's target
presents an excellent opportunity.
はぁ？
Huh?
Please help us find the tiger.
虎探しを手伝ってくれたまえ
No way!
嫌ですよ
国木田君は社に戻ってこのメモを社長に
Kunikida-kun, please go back to the Agency and give this to the president.
おい　二人だけで捕まえる気か
Hey, don't tell me you plan to catch
the tiger with just the two of you?
まずは情報の裏を取って
We should first confirm whether his information is accurate.
It's fine.
いいから
僕は嫌ですからね
I'm not doing this, okay?!
それってつまり「餌」ってことじゃないですか
This means you're going to use me as bait, right?
誰がそんな…
Who in their right mind would agree to that—
報酬出るよ
There's a reward.
Currently
penniless
What? Reward?
報酬？
報酬って
A reward?
No, no.
いやいやいや…
You're not gonna tempt me with that!
そんなものじゃ釣られませんからね
B-But just for reference,
ち　ちなみに　参考までに聞きますが　その報酬というのは
how much would the reward be?
About this much.
これくらい
Dazai-san, what are you reading?
太宰さん
何を読んでるんですか
A good book.
いい本
こんな暗い中でよく読めますね
I'm surprised you can read when it's this dark.
目はいいから
I have good vision.
Complete Guide to Suicide
それに　内容はもう凡て頭に入ってるし
Besides, I already know everything
that happens in this book.
じゃあ　なんで読んでるんですか
Why are you reading it, then?
A good book is always good,
no matter how many times you read it.
何度読んでもいい本はいい
本当に虎はここに現れるんでしょうか
Will the tiger really show up here?
It will.
現れる
心配要らない
Don't worry.
Even if it shows up, it's no match for me.
虎が現れても私の敵じゃないよ
I may not look like much,
こう見えても　「武装探偵社」の一隅だ
but I am an operative of the Armed Detective Agency.
You're really confident.
凄い自信ですね　なんか羨ましいです
I'm kind of jealous.
They called me a failure at the orphanage for as long as I can remember.
僕なんか　孤児院でもずっと「駄目な奴」って云われてて
そのうえ　今日の寝床も明日の食い扶持も知れない身で
And now, I don't even know where I'll sleep tonight, or if I'll eat tomorrow.
Get out, you failure!
出ていけ　この穀潰し
You'll never find a place where you belong!
天下のどこにもお前の居場所などありはせん
No one would care if someone like me were to die in a ditch somewhere.
確かにこんな奴がどこで野垂れ死んだって誰も気にしない
Yeah, I may as well be eaten by a tiger.
いや　いっそ虎に食われて死んだほうが…
Now, then...
却説
I think it'll be soon.
そろそろかな
What?!
い…今　奥で物音が
I... I just heard something back there.
そうだね
Yeah.
きっと奴ですよ　太宰さん
I bet that's the tiger, Dazai-san!
いや　風で何か落ちたんだろう
No, I think the wind just knocked something down.
It's the man-eater!
「人喰い虎」だ　僕を食いに来たんだ
It's come to eat me!
Calm down, Atsushi-kun.
落ち着きたまえ　敦君
Tigers don't just show up like that.
虎はあんな処からは来ない
How do you know for sure?!
どうしてわかるんですか
そもそも変なのだよ
Something wasn't quite right to begin with.
Just because their finances went south,
経営が傾いたからって　そんな理由で養護施設が児童を追放するかい
why would an orphanage banish a child?
It's not some farming village from a bygone era.
大昔の農村じゃないんだ
Eliminating one or two mouths to feed would hardly put a dent in their deficit.
いや　第一に経営が傾いたのなら
一人二人追放したところでどうにもならない
It'd make more sense to downsize
半分くらい減らして　他所の施設に移すのが筋だ
by transferring half of the kids to a different institution.
な　何を云ってるんです　太宰さん
What are you talking about, Dazai-san?
You came to this city two weeks ago.
君がこの街に来たのが二週間前
虎が街に現れたのも二週間前
The tiger also appeared in this city two weeks ago.
You were in Tsurumi four days ago.
君が鶴見の辺りにいたのが四日前
The tiger was also sighted there four days ago.
同じ場所で虎が目撃されたのも四日前
Remember what Kunikida-kun said?
国木田君が云っていたろう
The Armed Detective Agency is comprised of individuals with supernatural powers.
「武装探偵社」は異能を持つ輩の寄り合いだと
Though not a well-known fact,
あまり知られてはいないが　この世には異能の力を持つ者が少なからずいる
there are quite a few individuals who possess supernatural abilities in this world.
Some use their powers to achieve great success,
そしてその力で成功する者もいれば
力を制御できずに身を滅ぼす者もいる
while others fall into ruin as a result of being unable to control their powers.
I'm guessing that the institution
staff knew who the tiger was,
多分施設の人達は虎の正体を知っていたが
but declined to enlighten you.
君には教えなかったのだろう
君だけがわかっていなかったのだよ
You were the only one who remained ignorant.
You also have supernatural powers.
君も異能の力を持つ者だ
You have the ability to transform into
a wild beast in the moonlight.
現身に飢獣を降ろす
月下の能力者
That’s impressive.
こりゃ凄い
You could easily...
人間の首くらい
snap a person's neck.
簡単に圧し折れるね
おっと
Whoa, there.
獣に食い殺される最期というのも中々悪くないが
It wouldn't be terrible to meet one's end
being eaten by a beast,
君では私を殺せない
but you wont be able to kill me.
My ability is...
異能力
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
「人間失格」
No Longer Human.
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
No
Longer
Human
My ability allows me to dispel other abilities
私の能力は凡る他の異能力を　触れただけで無効化する
through a simple touch.
I'm not into hugging men.
男と抱き合う趣味はない
Thud
Hey, Dazai!
おい　太宰
Thud
ああ　遅かったな　国木田君
Oh, you're late, Kunikida-kun.
虎は捕らえたよ
I've captured the tiger.
まさか　この小僧が…
What, it's this boy?
He has the ability to transform into a tiger.
虎に変身する能力者だ
全く…
Jeez.
What was with this note?
何だこのメモは
"A tiger will appear in the warehouse
in the fifteenth district."
「十五番街の倉庫に虎が出る　逃げられぬ様周囲をかためろ」
"Secure the perimeter so that it can't escape."
実に簡潔でよいメモだ
It's an excellent, concise note.
要点が抜けとる
You've left out the most important detail!
次からは事前に説明しろ
Next time, explain in advance.
Thanks to you, I had to bring in
guys who weren't even on duty.
おかげで非番の奴らまで駆り出す始末だ
Take them out for drinks later.
後で皆に酒でも奢れ
Hey!
Yosano Akiko
Ability:
Thou Shalt Not Die
What, no casualties?
なんだい　怪我人はなしか
How boring.
つまんないねえ
Edogawa Rampo
Ability:
Ultra-Deduction
中々できるようになったじゃないか　太宰
You've come a long way, Dazai.
Though you still have a ways to go before you even can compare with me.
まあ　僕には遠く及ばないけどね
Miyazawa Kenji
Ability:
Be Not
Defeated
by the
Rain
But what shall we to do with him?
でも　この人をどうするんです
自覚はなかったわけでしょ
He didn't know he was doing it, right?
うん　そうだな
Yeah, you're right.
Kunikida Doppo
Ability:
Doppo
Poet
What do you think, Dazai?
どうする　太宰
The ward's designated him as a major threat.
一応区の災害指定猛獣だぞ
Dazai Osamu
Ability:
No
Longer
Human
I've already made a decision.
実はもう決めてある
僕なんか　孤児院でもずっと「駄目な奴」って云われてて
They called me a failure at the orphanage for as long as I can remember.
そのうえ　今日の寝床も明日の食い扶持も知れない身で
And now, I don't even know where I'll sleep tonight, or if I'll eat tomorrow.
確かにこんな奴がどこで野垂れ死んだって誰も気にしない
No one would care if someone like me were to die in a ditch somewhere.
Yeah, I may be better off eaten by a tiger.
いや　いっそ虎に食われて死んだほうが…
We'll make him one of us.
うちの社員にする
Nice!
なにそれ
Are you serious?
You're a real idiot, Dazai.
矢っ張り莫迦だな　太宰は
What gives you the right to decide that?
何の権限があって貴様は
よしよし　よーしよしっ
There, there.
起きろ少年
Wake up, boy!
Here, in a city teeming
with the supernatural,
怪奇ひしめくこの街を
変人揃いの探偵社
in a detective agency
teeming with eccentrics,
a strange tale is about to unfold.
これより始まる怪奇譚
This is only a sign of things to come.
A premonition, if you will.
これが先触れ　前兆し
Now...
却説
Huh?
あれ
I...
僕は…
Atsushi-kun.
敦君
Do you remember nothing at all
from when you were transformed?
変身中の記憶は全くなしかい
What are you talking about?
何のことです
Oh.
But your right hand's still transformed.
でもまだ右手に残ってる
Right hand?
右手？
What?!
Nakajima Atsushi
Ability:
Beast
Beneath
The
Moonlight
なに　なになに
What the?
What's this?
なにこれなにこれなにこれ
なんだなんだなんだー
What the hell?!
中島敦
Nakajima Atsushi!
これより君は私達の仲間になる
You'll become one of us.
From this day forth, you'll be a member of the Armed Detective Agency.
今日から君は「武装探偵社」の一員だ
Huh?
はい？
そ
の
重
い
足
を
膝
前
へ
導
く
その重い足を膝を前へ導く
负
责
人
Maki
负责人
力
は
何
だ
っ
て
Go
ahead
問
う
力は何だって Go ahead 問う
君
の
中
に
生
じ
る
衝
動
は
treasure
君の中に生じる衝動はtreasure
日
听
Cc.
长
田
Cris
翻
译
兰
樱
Naga
校
对
小
伍
江
本
物
か
偽
物
か
つ
れ
て
行
け
よ
日听
Cc.
长田Cris
翻译
兰樱
Naga
校对
小伍
小江
本物か偽物か つれて行けよ
空
想
の
彼
方
ま
で
僕
の
中
怠
慢
よ
空想の彼方まで 僕の中の怠慢よ
さ
ら
っ
て
も
い
よ
夢
で
も
时
间
轴
阿
水
压
制
Coolkid
时间轴
阿水
压制
Coolkid
さらってもいいよ 夢でも
届
き
そ
う
で
届
か
な
い
make
some
noise
届きそうで届かない make some noise
空
虚
な
日
常
は
輝
き
出
す
の
か
空虚な日常は輝き出すのか
吐
き
出
す
よ
う
に
し
て
前
に
漕
げ
ば
吐き出すようにして前に前に漕げば
僕
ら
の
未
来
は
加
速
し
て
い
く
だ
ろ
う
僕らの未来は加速していくだろう
今
こ
の
時
が
止
ま
る
と
し
て
も
今この時が止まるとしても
こ
の
呼
吸
ま
で
止
め
ら
れ
は
し
な
い
さ
この呼吸まで止められはしないさ
く
だ
ら
な
い
くだらない
ご
褒
美
ま
だ
？
ご褒美まだ？
It's been a long time since I've slept on a futon.
布団で寝たのは久しぶり
I feel reborn.
生き返った心地だ
Hey, brat.
こら　小僧
非常事態だ
There's an emergency.
Hightail it over to the detective agency.
さっさと探偵事務所に来い
非常事態って？
An emergency?
A bomber's taken a hostage and cozied up in our office.
爆弾魔が人質を取って事務所に立て篭もっているのだ
I don't want to go!
行きたくないです　僕
Next time on Bungou Stray Dogs, episode 2,
次回　「文豪ストレイドッグス」第二話
Episode 2
A Certain Bomb
"A Certain Bomb."
「或る爆弾」
Ability: Doppo Poet.
異能力　「独歩吟客」
僕が僕でいられる　理由を探していた
あなたの胸の中で　生きている僕がいるのならば
暗闇も長い坂道も　越えて行けるような僕になれるはず
それぞれに今を歩いてる僕らが笑えるように
生きている意味を確かめ合いながら進めるように
名前を呼ぶよ　あなたの名前を
あなたがあなたでいれるように
悲しみに暮れてあなたの涙がこぼれる時
寂しさに溢れて心がしぼんでく時
名前を呼ぶよ　あなたの名前を
僕の名前を呼んでくれたみたいに